One human only has the power to do so much.
一人の力など　たかが知れている
ならば私は自分で守れるだけ
That's why I'm going to protect...
...even if it's just a handful of them...
ほんのわずかでいい
...the ones most important to me.
大切な者を守ろう
A subordinate protects their subordinate, and so forth.
下の者が更に下を守る
That should be possible, even for us puny humans.
小さな人間なりに
そのくらいはできるはずだ
Geometric progression?
ネズミ算かよ
Which means this.
てぇことはだ
If you want to protect this whole country,
この国丸ごとみんな守るにゃ
you have to be at the top of the summit.
ネズミのてっぺんにいなきゃならねぇな
It must feel great up there, Hughes.
あそこはさぞかし気分がいいだろうな　ヒューズ
But I can't climb to the top with my own strength.
だが　私一人の力であそこに登り詰めることはできない
I'm sure of it.
その自信がある
What are you getting all worked up for?
何を威張ってるんだ　お前は
Sounds interesting.
おもしろそうじゃねぇか
I'm in.
ひと口乗ってやるよ
I want to see what kind of changes
your naive ideals will bring to this country.
お前の青臭い理想が
この国をどう変えるか見てみたい
Colonel...
大佐　大佐
Colonel.
Why not head to the nap room if you're tired?
お疲れでしたら　仮眠室へ行かれては
Yeah... sorry.
すまん
I wanted to finish up the documents I've started before I get transferred to Central.
セントラルに異動になる前に
やりかけの書類をまとめておきたくてな
I haven't slept much lately.
このところあまり寝ていない
It seemed you were dreaming about something.
何か夢を見ておられたようですが
What? Just a boring flashback.
なに　つまらん思い出だ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
で　こいつに蹴られた後はもう覚えてない
I don't remember anything after being kicked by this guy.
"Guardians with only souls",
"precious sacrifices", "being kept alive".
「魂のみの守護者」
「貴重な人柱」
「生かされている」
"Tattoo of Ouroboros", and
"transmutation circle for a philosopher's stone".
「ウロボスの入れ墨」に「賢者の石の錬成陣」
マルコー氏いわく
According to Dr. Marcoh,
the stones were used in Ishbal, as well...
イシュヴァールでも石が使われていた
There are too many mysteries for it to be an ordinary experiment.
ただの実験にしては　謎が多いですな
I'd like to look into it some more,
but the research lab is in ruins now.
これ以上調べようにも
今や研究所はガレキの山だしなぁ
Hmm...
うん
Seems like they're discussing something tricky...
なんだか難しそうな話をしてますが
I don't feel like getting involved in something dangerous again, so I refuse to listen!
これ以上危ないことに首を突っ込みたくないから
聞かない
Hey, you two...
ああ　君たち
Is this the Fullmetal Alchemist's recovery room?
鋼の錬金術師君の病室はここかね
Yes, he's in here...
はい　ここで
We may be able to discover something if we look through the court-martial chamber.
軍法会議所で犯罪リストでもあされば
何か出てくるかもしれねぇな
我が輩は　マルコー氏の下で
I'll go and investigate the ones who were participating in the research of the stones under Dr. Marcoh.
石の研究に携わっていた者たちを調べてみましょう
Sorry to intrude.
失礼するよ
キ…キング　ブラッドレイ大総統
F-Führer-President... King Bradley!
Quiet down. You can be at ease.
ああ静かに　そのままでよろしい
閣下　なぜこのような所に
Your Excellency, may I ask why you are here?
Why I'm here?
なぜって　お見舞い
To visit this boy, of course.
Are you fond of melon at all?
メロンは嫌いかね
あっ　どうも
Oh... thank you.
Wait, something's wrong here!
じゃなくて
Seems like you've been doing a lot of investigating of the military leadership, Major Armstrong.
軍上層部をいろいろ調べているようだな
アームストロング少佐
はあっ　あっ　いや　その
Huh?! Well... that's...
How did you...
なぜ　それを
私の情報網を甘く見るな
Don't underestimate my intelligence network.
そして　エドワード·エルリック君
And you, Edward Elric...
賢者の石だね
The philosopher's stone, right?
Just how much did you find out?
Depending on that, I may have to...
どこまで知った
場合によっては
冗談だ
I'm joking!
No need to get tense.
そう構えずともよい
What?
軍内部で不穏な動きがあることは私も知っていてな
I, too, was aware there have been
disquieting activities within the military.
I've always wanted to do something about them, but...
どうにかせねばと思っているのだが
Oh, that's...
あっ　それは
A list of people who were researching the philosopher's stones, eh?
賢者の石の研究をしていた者の名簿か
Every one of them has been reported missing.
この者たち　全員行方不明になっているぞ
What?!
They have been reported missing a few days prior to the destruction of Research Laboratory 5.
第五研究所が崩壊する数日前にな
The enemy is always ahead of us.
敵は常に我々の先を行っておる
Even with my intelligence network,
we still don't know the scale of it all,
そして私の情報網をもってしても
その大きさも目的も
どこまで敵の手が入り込んでいるかも
their objectives, or how close they are to achieving them.
掴めていないのが現状だ
つまり　探りを入れるのはかなり危険であると
So you're saying it's extremely dangerous for us to look into it.
That's right.
Lt. Colonel Hughes,
ヒューズ中佐　アームストロング少佐
Major Armstrong,
Elric Brothers,
エルリック兄弟
I've decided you all are trustworthy people.
君たちは　信用に足る人物だと判断した
I forbid you to continue investigating this matter or to disclose it to others!
これ以上この件に首を突っ込むことも
これを口外することも許さん
You cannot trust anyone in a situation like this,
when you cannot even distinguish friend from foe!
誰が敵か味方かも分からぬこの状況で
何人も信用してはならん
軍内部すべて敵と思い慎んで行動せよ
Regard all of the military as your foe and proceed carefully!
However...
だが
When the time comes, I will have many tasks for all of you.
時が来たら君たちには存分に働いてもらうので
So be prepared.
覚悟しておくように
Yes, sir!
はっ
Your Excellency!
閣下
Where have you gone, Your Excellency?!
大総統閣下は　いずこ
ああ　いかん
Ah, drats! Here comes my annoying subordinate.
うるさい部下が追ってきた
I snuck out of my office, after all.
仕事をこっそり抜け出してきたのでな
では　さらば
Farewell!
エド　あれ
Hey, Ed.
Huh?
どうしたの　みんな
What are you guys doing?
Let's just say... a storm just went by.
いや　嵐が通り過ぎた
I went out and bought the tickets you asked for.
頼まれてた切符　買ってきたよ
Tomorrow's afternoon train, right?
明日のお昼の汽車でよかったんだよね
Yeah, thanks.
サンキュー
Why are you in such a rush?
Your wounds haven't even healed yet.
なんだ　せわしないな
ケガも治りきってなかろうに
I can't stay in a place reeking of antiseptics like this forever.
いつまでもこんな消毒液臭い所にこもってられっか
Where are you going this time?
今度はどこへ行くんだ
Dublith?
ダブリス
Yeah.
After discussing it with Al, we decided to stop by our master's place.
アルとも話し合って
師匠のところへ行こうってことになってさ
I'm scared, Brother...
やっぱ怖いよ　兄さん
We're probably going to get killed!
僕たち　きっと殺されるよ
C-Courage, my little brother!
たっ耐えろ　弟
I'm just as scared as you are!
オレだって怖いんだ
What kind of person is your master...
あんたたちの師匠って
Dublith is quite far from here.
ダブリスとはまた随分と遠い
Where is it?
どの辺なの
Let's see... It's here. It's right in the middle of the South.
うんとね　ここ　南部の真ん中辺り
W-What?!
なっ　なんだ
This place! Before Dublith!
ここよ　ここ　ダブリスの手前
機械鎧の聖地　ラッシュバレー
The Holy Land of Automails, Rush Valley!
I've always wanted to go there!
一度　行ってみたかったの
Please take me! Please take me!
連れてって連れてって連れていけ連れてけ
Take me! You better take me!
一人で行け　そんな所
Why don't you go by yourself?
Who's going to pay for the trip, then?
誰が旅の費用を払うのよ
You're planning on making me  pay for it?!
オレにたかる気か
まあまあ
Sure, why not? It's on the way, after all.
いいんじゃない　ついでだし
I guess it's okay...
しょうがねぇな
やった　ははははっ
Hooray!
ばっちゃんに電話してくるね
I'm going to give Granny a call!
Yeah, she'll make a grand wife.
うん　ありゃいい嫁さんになるぞ
Don't tell me  that!
オレに言うな
Not as grand as my wife, though!
まあ　うちの嫁さんほどじゃないけどなぁ
Well, Papa's going to be on his way!
じゃあパパ　行ってきまちゅよ
Are you going to come home early today, Papa?
パパ　今日は早く帰って来るの
Hmm, I wonder?
うん　どうかなぁ
Papa's got a lot of work to do!
パパお仕事いっぱいだからね
But I'll come home as soon as I can!
でもなるべく早く帰って来ちゃうぞぉ
You're going to be late.
遅刻しますよ
You're going to be leaving today, right, Winry?
ウィンリィちゃん　今日出発だっけな
I can't see you off because of work, so...
仕事で見送りに行けないけど
Take care of yourself.
元気でな
ヒューズさん　ほんとにお世話になりました
I'm truly indebted to you, Mr. Hughes.
Be sure to drop by if you ever come to Central again.
セントラルに来た時は　また必ず遊びに来てくれよ
Think of it as your home.
自分の家だと思ってさ
And give my regards to those boys, too.
それと　あいつらにもよろしくな
Okay!
はい
Good luck at work, Papa!
パパ頑張ってね
See you!
いってらっしゃい
なんで急に師匠のところへ行こうなんて思ったの
Why did you decide to go visit your master all of a sudden?
Two reasons.
理由は二つ
First off, we've kind of been on a losing streak.
最近どうにも負けっぱなしでよ
What?!
はあ　ケンカ強くなりたくて行くの
You're going because you want to get stronger?!
What are you guys, muscleheads?
あんたらケンカバカ
Idiot! It's not that simple!
バッキャロ　そんな単純なもんじゃねぇや
We don't just want to get stronger physically, but should we say mentally, too...
ケンカだけじゃなくて　中身もっていうか
Right?
なあ
Yeah.
そうそう
Anyway, we feel like we'll be able to get stronger if we visit our master.
兎に角　師匠のところに行けば
なんか強くなれる気がする
オレはもっともっと強くなりたい
I want to become far stronger than I am now.
And your second reason?
二つ目は
賢者の石について師匠に聞く
I want to ask about philosopher's stones.
The real truth that is beyond truth...
真実の奥の更なる真実
We never found out the meaning of those words, after all.
結局分からずじまいだからね
Our master might know something about it.
師匠なら　何か知ってるかもしんない
We can't be caring about how we're going to look out there.
もうなりふり構ってらんねぇや
We're going to ask our master while being prepared to be killed...
師匠にぶっ殺される覚悟で聞いて
Ask...
聞いて　聞いて
It was a short-lived life.
短い人生だったなぁ
I wish I could have had a girlfriend, at least...
せめて彼女だけでもつくっておきたかったよ
あんたたちの師匠って
What kind of person is your master?
A riot in Lior?
リオールの暴動
Yes.
ええ
Apparently, the riot caused by some Leto cult
deceiving the citizens has finally calmed down.
レト教とかいう新興宗教が住民を騙したってやつ
やっと治まったらしいですよ
I see...
With Ishbal and other riots...
the East sure have their hands full.
イシュヴァールやら暴動やら
東部も大変だな
Not just the East, but there are riots and border wars
sparking up in the North and the West.
東部だけでなく
北も西も「暴動だ　国境戦だ」と
Mountains of corpses everywhere, huh...
あっちもこっちも死体の山か
We may even get a coup soon...
そのうち国家転覆するんじゃ
Where are you headed, Lt. Colonel?
中佐　どちらへ
書庫へ行ってくる
To the library.
Riots throughout Lior.
リオール　各地の暴動
賢者の石　材料は人間
The ingredients of philosopher's stones are humans...
What we did in Ishbal...
イシュヴァールでオレたちがやったこと
Whoa now, who's the mastermind behind all of this?
おいおい　どこのどいつだ
こんなこと考えやがるのは
I've got to hurry and let the Führer-President know...
早く大総統に
Nice to meet you, Lt. Colonel Hughes.
はじめまして　ヒューズ中佐
Or should I say... farewell?
それとも…
さよならの方がいいかしら
イカす入れ墨してるな
Cool tattoo you've got there.
知りすぎたわね　ヒューズ中佐
You found out too much, Lt. Colonel Hughes.
Dammit...
くそっ
「くそっ」はこっちのセリフだわ
That's something I  should be saying.
Oh, Lt. Colonel Hughes.
あら　ヒューズ中佐
If you're here to call someone about your family again-
また家庭自慢の電話で
Lt. Colonel, you're bleeding!
中佐　血が
なんでもねぇ　電話借りるぞ
It's nothing. I need to use the phone...
I need to call the Führer-President building...
大総統府に
悪い　邪魔したな
Sorry to bother you...
Lt. Colonel!
えっ　中佐
Hello? You've reached Eastern Headquarters.
はい　東方司令部
ロイ·マスタング大佐につないでくれ
Let me talk to Roy... Colonel Roy Mustang.
We're not permitted to relay direct calls from an outside line.
外線からの電話はつなげない決まりになっておりまして
セントラルのヒューズ中佐だ
I'm Lt. Colonel Hughes from Central!
I'm calling from a phone booth because of an emergency!
緊急で外から掛けてる
Please give me the code.
コードをお願いします
What a bother!
ああ　もうめんどくせぇ
アンクル　シュガー　オリバー　エイト　ゼロ　ゼロ
Uncle-Sugar-Oliver-Eight-Zero-Zero!
コード確認しました　しばらくお待ちください
I've verified the code.
One moment, please.
早くしろ　軍がやべぇ
Hurry up!
The military is in danger!
Could you put down the receiver, Lt. Colonel?
受話器を置いていただけますか　中佐
The receiver, please.
さあ　受話器を
ロス少尉　じゃねぇな
2nd Lt. Ross... or not.
Who are you?
誰だあんた
マリア·ロス少尉です
I'm 2nd Lt. Maria Ross. Have you forgotten?
お忘れですか
いいや違う
No, you're not.
ロス少尉は左目の下に泣きぼくろがあるんだよ
2nd Lt. Ross has a mole under her left eye!
Huh? Really?
ああ　そうだっけ
うっかりしてたよ
I was careless.
How's this?
これでいっかな
What the hell...
なんだってんだ　夢でも見てるみたいだぜ
It's as if I'm dreaming.
Your quick-wittedness brought the end of you, Lt. Colonel Hughes.
頭の回転が早いばっかりに
とんだ災難だったね　ヒューズ中佐
Hey now, give me a break.
おいおい　勘弁してくれ
I've got a wife and a daughter waiting for me at home.
家で女房子供が待ってるんだ
There's no way...
ここで死ぬわけには　いかねぇんだよ
...I can die here!
Perfect staging, right?
いい演出だろう
くそったれ
Damn you!!!
Lt. Colonel Hughes from Central is on a public line.
セントラルのヒューズ中佐から　一般回線で通信です
Again?
またか　つなげ
Put him through.
It's me.
私だ　娘自慢なら聞かんぞ
If it's about your daughter again, I'm hanging up.
ヒューズ
Hughes?
Hughes...
ヒューズ　おい　ヒューズ
Hey, Hughes!
Humans are so foolish.
人間ってほんと愚かだよね
Risking their lives for something so stupid.
ムダなことに命懸けちゃったりしてさ
エリシア　グレイシア
Elicia... Gracia...
ごめんな
I'm sorry...
早く帰るって　約束…
I don't think I can... keep my promise...
おおっ　うめぇ
Wow, this is delicious!
These apple pies are awesome!
このアップルパイ　最高
Miss Gracia is such a good cook!
グレイシアさんって　すっごく料理上手なんだよ
知ってるよ
I know that.
The quiche she made for us once was really good.
前に作ってもらったキッシュもすっげぇうまかった
体を取り戻したら食べたい物リストに
It's on my "list of things to eat when I get my body back".
ちゃんと入ってるもんね
She taught me how to make it, so I'll bake one for you when you get your body back, Al.
作り方教えてもらったから
アルの体が戻ったら　焼いてあげるね
Yay!
やった あははっ
ヒューズさんもグレイシアさんも　すごくいい人だった
Mr. Hughes and Miss Gracia are both wonderful people.
Lt. Colonel Hughes is such a doting father...
and kind of annoying because he's so meddlesome.
ヒューズ中佐って　親バカで世話焼きで
鬱陶しいんだよなぁ
He always came to poke fun at you in your hospital room, didn't he?
いっつも病室に兄さんをからかいに来てたよね
Seriously.
ほんとに
He's always saying he's busy with work, yet he paid me a visit every day.
仕事が忙しいって言いながら
しょっちゅう見舞いに来やがんの
We have to thank him next time.
今度何かお礼をしなきゃね
Yeah.
ああ
Mama... why are they burying Papa?
ママ　どうしてパパ埋められちゃうの
エリシア
Elicia...
Papa won't be able to go to work if they do that.
そんなことしたら　パパお仕事できなくなっちゃうよ
Elici...
エリシ…
Papa said he had a lot of work to do!
パパ　お仕事いっぱいあるって言ってたもん
嫌だよう　埋めないでよ
Stop!
Don't bury him!
Papa!!!
パパ
Specially promoted two ranks after being killed in the line of duty.
殉職で二階級特進　ヒューズ准将か
Brigadier General Hughes... huh?
私の下について助力すると言っていたヤツが
You said you were going to work under me and support me.
上に行ってどうする
What's the point if you surpass my rank?
バカ者が
Idiot...
大佐
Colonel.
錬金術師というのは嫌な生き物だな　中尉
Alchemists are unpleasant creatures, aren't they, Lieutenant?
今　頭の中で人体錬成の理論を
I'm desperately putting together the theory of human transmutation in my head.
必死になって組み立てている自分がいる
I feel like I know how those boys felt when they tried to transmute their mother.
あの子らが母親を錬成しようとした気持ちが
今なら分かる気がする
大丈夫ですか
Are you all right?
大丈夫だ
Yeah.
いかん　雨が降ってきたな
Ah, it looks like it's beginning to rain.
No, I don't think so...
いいえ　雨なんて
いや　雨だよ
No, it's raining all right.
You're right.
そうですね
Let's go back.
戻りましょう
We'll catch colds.
ここは　冷えます
「書庫へ行く」と出ていきましてね
He left the room saying that
he was going to go to the library.
That was the last I saw of the Lt. Colonel.
それが　中佐を見た最後でした
Did he fight with someone in here?
何者かと争ったのか
Most likely.
おそらく
There were bloodstains from the room to the hallway.
室内から廊下へと　血痕が残されていました
そして　次に向かったのが
And his next destination was...
中佐は　ケガをしたまま　電話を掛けようとして
Lt. Colonel tried to make a phone call,
even while he was injured...
But... he left without doing so.
でも　どこへも掛けずに　出ていってしまったんです
He realized something in the court-martial chamber...
軍法会議所で何かに気づき
...and took the trouble to contact me from the outside when he could have called from within the building.
所内で通信できたものを
わざわざ外に出て私に連絡を取ろうとした
The telephone operator in the Eastern Headquarters heard Hughes say, "The military is in danger".
東方司令部の電話交換手は
「軍がやばい」というヒューズの言葉を聞いている
なんだあいつは何を伝えようとした
What is it?
What was he trying to tell me?
大佐　アームストロング少佐をお連れしました
Colonel, I've brought Major Armstrong.
We have an idea of the ones who murdered Lt. Colonel Hughes.
ヒューズ中佐を
殺害したと思われる者たちの目星はついています
Then why don't you take them into custody?!
ならば　なぜさっさと捕らえない
We have an idea, but we don't know exactly who they are.
目星はついておりますが　どこの誰かも分からんのです
どういうことだ　詳しく話せ
What do you mean? Tell me in detail.
できません
I cannot.
I, a Colonel, am telling you to speak.
大佐である私が話せと言っているのだ
Are you going to disobey a senior officer?!
上官に逆らうというのか
I cannot speak.
話せません
Understood.
分かった
Sorry for calling you out here.
呼び出してすまなかった
You may go.
もう行っていいぞ
Yes, sir.
はっ
Sir, I forgot to mention.
そういえば我が輩　言い忘れておりました
The Elric Brothers had been staying here until a few days ago.
数日前まで　エルリック兄弟が滞在しておりましてな
The Elric Brothers?
エルリック兄弟が
Yes, the Elric Brothers.
そう　エルリック兄弟です
Did they find what they were looking for?
彼らの探し物は見つかったのかね
No.
いいえ
What they are looking for is almost legendary.
何しろそれは　伝説級の代物ですので
I see. Thanks.
そうか　ありがとう
これといった情報は得られませんでしたね
We couldn't get much out of him, could we?
Seriously...
いやまったく　少佐はお人よしだ
The Major is truly good-natured.
He said specifically,
"ones who murdered Lt. Colonel Hughes".
「ヒューズを殺害したと思われる者たち」ということは
Which means there were several.
相手は複数
It could be that they're working as an organization.
ひょっとすると組織として動いている者たち
「大佐である私の命令であろうと言うわけにはいかない」
If he can't speak, even under order from a colonel,
that means someone higher ranked than me is imposing silence on him.
ということは
私以上の者が少佐に口止めしているということ
We can assume the top of the military is behind it.
軍上層部絡みと考えていいだろう
そして　「エルリック兄弟の探し物」
And the thing the Elric Brothers are looking for...
In other words, the philosopher's stone.
即ち賢者の石だ
An organization that has a hand in the military leadership, the philosopher's stone, and Lt. Colonel Hughes...
軍上層部にかかわる組織と　賢者の石と　ヒューズ中佐
Just how does it all relate...
一体どんなつながりが
As for now, we don't know.
今はまだ分からん
だが　セントラルに転属したら
But once I get transferred to Central, I'll investigate the leadership and find out who killed Hughes.
上層部を探って
ヒューズを殺したヤツを必ずいぶり出してやる
公私混同とは　あなたらしくないですね
It's unlike you to mix up private and public matters.
There are no "private" or "public" matters involved.
「公」も「私」もあるものか
Aiming to become Führer-President and avenging Hughes' death...
大総統の地位をもらうのも
ヒューズの仇を討つのも
...are both my will as an individual.
すべて私一個人の意志だ
上層部に食らいつくぞ
Our target will be the military leadership. You're coming with me, right?
ついてくるか
何を今更
Like I'll back down now.
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
銀時計を奪った少女パニーニャを追って
Ed and Al run through Rush Valley, chasing after Paninya, a girl who stole Ed's silver pocket watch,
エドたちはラッシュバレーを走る
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
その先に　何が待っているかを知らず
although they have no idea what's awaiting them.
次回　鋼の錬金術師　FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
第十一話　ラッシュバレーの奇跡
Episode 11, Miracle at Rush Valley.
少年が刻んだ言葉は決意　それとも…
The words the boy engraved were words of resolve.
Or could they be...